主演：利亚姆・尼森
导演：皮埃尔・莫瑞尔
编剧：吕克・贝松 罗伯特・马克・卡门
【 飓 风 营 救 】
- 米尔斯先生 你好吗? - 很好
- Mr. Mills, how are you? - I'm fine.
- 你呢? - 很好
- How are you? - Fine.
- 我猜你还想再看一遍? - 你不介意的话
- I suppose you wanna see it again? - Lf you don't mind.
- 你知道放在哪里 - 哦 是的
- You know where it is. - Oh, yeah.
如果你每次来看机子我都收你一元...
If I charged you a dollar every time you came to examine the machine...
...都够你买一台了 内行都用这个
...you'd probably own it. It's the one all the pros use.
玛丽亚・凯莉 碧昂丝 格温・史蒂芬尼
Mariah Carey. Beyonce. Gwen Stefani.
真的? 碧昂丝是谁?
Really? Who's Beyonce?
开玩笑呢 我要了
Just kidding. I'll take it.
等等 先生 家长聚会在前面
Excuse me, sir. The adult party's in the front.
- 我是金米的父亲 - 不好意思 我就是为她父亲工作的
- I'm Kim's father. - Excuse me, I work for her father.
- 我是她的亲生父亲 - 没事 西里尔 我来
- Her real father. - It's okay, Cyril. I got it.
- 你好 布莱恩 - 勒诺
- Hello, Bryan. - Lenore.
我只是来给金米礼物的
I just wanted to give Kim her present.
有专门给孩子们放礼物的地方
We're letting the kids have their space.
- 就跟其他人的放一起吧 - 我想亲手交给她
- Put it with the others. - I wanna give it to her myself.
- 仍是我行我素啊 - 哦 拜托 列尼
- Still having trouble following the rules. - Oh, come on, Lennie.
- 叫你不要这么叫了 - 抱歉 勒诺
- I've asked you not to call me that. - Excuse me. Lenore.
- 爸爸! - 哦 亲爱的
- Dad! - Oh, my darling.
- 嗨 - 你好 我的宝贝
- Hi. - Hello, my sweet.
- 生日快乐 - 我在跟你爸爸说...
- Happy birthday. - I was telling your father...
...我们如何放置礼物的 - 给你
...how we arranged the presents. - Here.
拆了这个礼物 而不拆其他的...
It's bad manners to open the one...
...可不是个好习惯 - 来 打开它
...and not the others. - Go on. Open it.
- 好酷哦 - 卡拉OK机?
- Cool. - A karaoke machine?
- 我记得她想成为一个歌星 - 那是12岁的事了 布莱恩
- Well, I figured she wants to be a singer. - When she was 12, Bryan.
- 我们都变了 - 谢谢 爸爸
- We've moved on. - Thank you, Daddy.
你喜欢就好
My pleasure.
- 我还是想当歌手 不要告诉妈妈 - 好的
- I still wanna be a singer. Don't tell Mom. - You got it.
给 照张相作个纪念
Here. One for the book.
- 我们有职业摄影师 - 笑一笑 宝贝
- We have a professional photographer. - Big smile, sweetie.
真是我的乖女儿
That's my girl.
哦 天哪 哦 天哪!
Oh, my God. Oh, my God!
哦 天哪! 哦 天哪! 哦 天哪!
Oh, my God! Oh, my God! Oh, my God!
哦 天...斯图尔特!
Oh, my... Stuart!
斯图尔特 我爱你! 我爱你! 我爱你!
Stuart, I love you! I love you! I love you!
生日快乐 宝贝
Happy birthday, sweetie.
- 哦 斯图尔特 太意外了 - 我知道
- Oh, Stuart, you're impossible. - I know.
- 嗨 布莱恩 - 斯图尔特
- Hey, Bryan. - Stuart.
- 她不再是个小女孩了 是吧? - 我想是的
- She's not a little girl anymore, huh? - I guess not.
- 留下来吃午饭吧? - 不了 谢谢
- Will you join us for lunch? - No, thanks.
我只是来这祝她生日快乐的
I just wanted to be here to wish her a happy birthday.
- 很高兴见到你 布莱恩 - 我也是
- Good to see you, Bryan. - You too.
谢谢
Thanks.
- 嗨 - 嗨
- Hey. - Hey.
你忘了
You forgot.
进来
Come on in.
我都打电话提醒你了 五月的第三个星期六 对吧?
It's not like I didn't call to remind you. Third Saturday in May?
- 牛排 红酒? 很熟悉吧? - 也许他脑子里塞了太多事了
- Red meat, red wine? Sound familiar? - He probably had a lot on his mind.
是啊 退休工人的忙碌生活 每天都是个新冒险
Yeah, the busy life of a retiree. Every day a new adventure.
不过退休了都做些什么? 睡睡觉? 打打高尔夫?
What does a retiree do, anyway? Take naps? Play golf?
- 搭讪富孀? - 一上午有的忙了
- Hit on rich widows? - That takes care of the morning.
得了 伙计们 你们知道我在这的原因
Yeah, well, come on, guys. You know why I'm here.
是啊 怎么了?
Yeah, how's that going?
没什么 我们今天给她庆生
Okay. We had her birthday today.
你们相信我的金米都17岁了吗?
Can you believe my Kimmy's 17?
17岁?
Seventeen?
- 为了金米 - 列尼还恨你吗?
- To Kim. - Lennie still got a hard-on for you?
她不再是列尼了 她叫勒诺
She's not Lennie anymore. She's Lenore.
哦 她还恨你呢
Oh, she's still got a hard-on.
- 她丈夫呢? - 还是老样子 很配
- And the husband? - The same. Perfect.
- 要是追根究底总会发现点什么 - 想要我们帮你查尽管说
- Dig deep enough, there's always shit. - We can dig if you want us to dig.
什么 你觉得他没查过?
What, you think he hasn't done it already?
谢谢 伯尼
Thank you, Bernie.
- 金米怎么样? - 很好 她很好
- How's Kimmy? - Good. She's good.
是吗? 她还是没回来住?
Yeah? She sleep over yet?
是的 我们在努力
Well, let's say we're working on it.
为了和她亲近 你放弃了自己的生活...
She appreciate the fact that you've given up your life...
...对此她有谢过你吗?
...in order to be closer to her?
什么生活 哈?
What a life, huh?
嘿 还记得头儿失踪后 我们在贝鲁特的事吗?
Hey, remember Beirut after the chief disappeared?
布莱和那个疯狂的真主党酋长耗上了?
Bry was in deep with that crazy sheik from Hezbollah?
那家伙扬言要把我们都弄进去 然后自己就失踪了
The guy said he'd get us inside then disappeared.
为了性命 我们可是狼狈地逃出那鬼地方......
We're scrambling to get the hell out...
...那时你在哪?
...before we get taken down and where are you?
我答应过绝不会错过她的生日
I promised never to miss her birthday.
是啊 当他们发觉你悄然离开...
Yeah, that went down well at Langley...
...跑去9公里外参加你女儿的生日派对...
...when they found out you flew the coop...
...兰格利那边也没怎样 (CIA总部位于弗吉尼亚州费尔费克斯县麦克林区内的兰格利小区)
...to attend your child's birthday 9000 miles away.
你当时说你的下个目的地是哪来着?
Where did you say your next posting was?
去北极观察企鹅 我想是这个
The Arctic Circle spying on penguins, I believe it was.
不 企鹅在南极
No, penguins live in Antarctica.
事实上 是在阿拉斯加 你到底想说什么 萨姆?
Actually, it was Alaska. What's your point, Sam?
我的意思是 只要你一句话 我们随时欢迎你回来
My point is we have an open space. Say the word, it's yours.
谁要半熟的牛排?
Who likes theirs rare?
- 伙计们 - 再见 布莱恩
- Guys. - See you, Bryan.
- 晚安 伙计们 - 拜拜 布莱
- Good night, guys. - See you, Bry.
嘿 听着 听着 听着 不开玩笑...
Hey, look, look, look. All kidding aside...
...花时间陪金米 弥补以前的空白是件好事
...it's a great thing trying to make up for lost time with Kimmy.
但明天的工作呢? 就在眼前
But tomorrow's job? Right here.
工作四小时 2500元报酬...
Four hours' work, 2500 bucks...
...只是护送某个女歌星来回演唱会
...just for taking some pop diva to and from her concert.
- 还缺一个人 - 歌星?
- We're one short. - A singer?
我不清楚她是否算得上歌手 她更像棵摇钱树
I don't know if you'd call her a singer. More like a cash cow.
唱片销量达到两千万张 却还不到25岁
Twenty million records sold already and she's not even 25.
工作很容易
Job's a piece of cake.
送她去那 再送回来 里面由他们自己人负责
We get her there and back. Inside, they've got their own people.
- 好的 - 好的 好的?
- Okay. - Okay. Okay?
- 是啊 - 答应了?
- Yeah. - Like that's it?
对
Yeah.
- 太好了 就像以前一样 - 比以前更好 不会有人丧命
- It'll be perfect. Just like old times. - Better. No one gets killed.
- 明天见 晚安 伙计们 - 再见
- Tomorrow. Good night, guys. - See you.
- 坐后面去 温迪 - 我老是坐后面
- Get in the back, Wendy. - I always get in the back.
夫人 不好意思 请继续往前
Ma'am, if you don't mind, I suggest you keep moving.
抱歉 我妈才叫夫人
My mother is ma'am, if you don't mind.
- 来 时间到了 走吧 - 好的
- Come on, it's time now. Let's go. - Okay.
伯尼 凯西 你们守在这 布莱 你进去
Bernie, Casey, you're out here. Bry, you're in the room.
好的
Okay.
走吧 走吧 走吧
Let's go, let's go, let's go.
谢谢光临
Thank you for coming.
哇 好漂亮
Wow, it was beautiful.
谢谢 你叫什么来着?
Thanks. What did you say your name was again?
米尔斯 布莱恩・米尔斯
Mills. Bryan Mills.
- 很高兴见到你 布莱恩・米尔斯 - 很高兴见到你
- Nice to meet you, Bryan Mills. - You too.
- 该你了 快 我们走吧 - 好的 伙计们
- You're on. Come on, let's go now. - Okay, guys.
等一下 小姐
Excuse me, miss.
我有个女儿想成为一个歌手 我想问问你有没有什么建议
I've a daughter who wants to be a singer and was wondering if you had any tips.
有啊
Yeah, I do.
告诉她别走这条路
Tell her to pick another career.
我想到有次我们在等空袭...
I got one. We're waiting on an air strike...
...我们等啊等 然后我的卫星电话响了
...and we're waiting and then my satellite phone rings.
- 哪位? - 喂?
- Who is it? - Hello?
- 我们要干掉的那家伙 - 宝贝
- The guy we're to terminate. - Honey.
- 他想知道我们是否要喝点茶 - 抱歉 各位 是金米
- He'd like to know if we want some tea. - Sorry, guys, it's Kim.
噪音?
The noise?
我在演唱会现场呢
I'm at a concert.
你知道这首歌? 是吗?
You know this song? Yeah?
对 是她 不 不 不 我不是来看演唱会的
Yep, that's her. No, no, no, I'm not attending.
我...我不是来看的
I'm... I'm not attending.
我帮朋友做些保安工作
I'm helping some friends out with security.
当然我见到她了
Well, of course I met her.
你以为谁在保护她啊?
Who do you think's guarding her?
听到你这么有兴趣 我很开心
I'm glad you're impressed.
嘿 很高兴接到你的电话
Hey, I'm happy you called.
你能打给我 我很开心 什么?
I'm happy you called. What?
午餐? 明天?
Lunch? Tomorrow?
当然 没问题 我知道那地方
Sure, sure. I know the place.
十二点半
Twelve-thirty it is.
到时见
I'll see you then.
- 他来了 然后呢? - 怎么了?
- Here he is. And? - What happened?
- 她要和我一起吃午饭 - 很好
- She wants to have lunch. - Okay.
- 就我们俩 - 不错 太棒了
- Just the two of us. - All right. Fantastic.
看见没? 有进展 棒极了
See? There's progress. That's great.
谁把门打开了? 布莱 带她离开这 你领路
Who left that gate open? Bry, get her out of here. Take the lead.
- 走吧! - 走 走!
- Move! - Go, go!
再来些保安!
More security here now!
就是这样 走吧
That's it. Move.
凯西!
Casey!
伯尼 准备行动 准备行动
Bernie, stand by, stand by.
- 走 走 快走 - 小心头
- Go, go, go. - Watch your head.
给 喝点 糖水可以压惊
Here, take this. The sugar will take the edge off the shock.
来 来 再喝点
Come on, come on, drink some more.
好了 没事了 你安全了
It's okay. It's okay. You're safe.
你现在很安全
You're safe now.
伯尼
Bernie.
凯西 兰博
Casey. Rambo.
认真点 布莱 你该考虑下加入我们
Seriously, Bry, you should think about coming with us.
你已尝到甜头了 你还可以拿到更多
You've got the edge. There's more of this to be had.
- 她明年要上大学了吧? - 是的
- She's going to college next year? - Yep.
- 你就要失去她了 - 一年够我找回她了
- You're gonna lose her. - That gives me a year to find her.
米尔斯先生 她想要见你
Mr. Mills, she'd like to see you.
- 好点了吗? - 好多了
- How are you feeling? - Better.
你的女儿想当歌手?
So your daughter wants to be a singer?
是啊 从她5岁起
Yep, since she was 5.
歌手的生活并不如其他人所想的那样
It's not what everyone thinks it is.
一旦没了新鲜感 就只剩下酒店和机场的东奔西跑
Once the glam wears off, it's just a lot of hotel rooms, lots of airports.
她要的就是这个
It's what she wants.
第一个号码是我的声乐老师吉奥的
The first number is Gio, my vocal coach.
如果他说行 就代表她能唱
If he says she can sing, she can sing.
他会给她必要的指导 学费我来
He'll give her coaching she needs, the fee is on me.
第二个号码是我经纪人的
The second number is my manager.
如果吉奥肯定了她 他就能为她创造机会
If Gio clears her, he'll make sure she gets a shot.
- 谢谢 - 不 米尔斯先生 是我要谢谢你
- Thank you. - No, Mr. Mills, thank you.
- 她来了 - 爸爸
- There she is. - Dad.
- 嗨 宝贝 - 嗨
- Hi, sweetie. - Hey.
- 你好 - 你好
- Hi. - Hi.
不要那么激动
Don't look so excited.
我只是很惊讶 我以为就我和金米
I was just surprised. I thought it was just gonna be Kim and I.
我叫妈妈来的
I asked Mom to come.
一份覆盆子香蕉奶昔加樱桃 你最喜欢的
One raspberry-banana milkshake, extra cherries, just the way you like it.
- 谢谢 - 列尼...勒诺
- Thanks. - Lennie... Lenore.
- 你要点什么? - 不了 谢谢
- Would you like something? - I'm fine, thanks.
那么?
So?
爸爸 你猜怎么着
So, Dad, guess what.
- 你知道我朋友阿曼达吧? - 嗯
- You know my friend Amanda? - Yep.
她的表姐妹邀请我们一起去巴黎度假
Her cousins asked us to spend vacation with them in Paris.
很酷吧?
How cool is that?
- 你怎么想去巴黎了? - 爸爸 不会吧?
- Why do you want to go to Paris? - Dad. Hello?
罗浮宫 印象派博物馆 毕加索博物馆
The Louvre, the lmpressionist museum, the Picasso Museum.
我不知道你会对艺术这么感兴趣
I didn't know you were so into art.
真的假的? 我都去过现代艺术博物馆一百多次了
Are you kidding? I've been to the MOMA, like, a hundred times.
阿曼达去年夏天去的 回来后她都能说法语了
Amanda went last summer, she came back, she could practically speak French.
因为你还未满18岁...
And because you're under 18...
...所以你要得到我的允许才能出国?
...you need my permission to leave the country?
爸爸 求你了 我真的真的很想去
Dad, please. I really, really wanna go.
她们的公寓超棒的 可以俯瞰塞纳河
They've got this sick apartment overlooking the river.
- 就你和阿曼达? - 还有她的表姐妹
- Just you and Amanda? - And her cousins.
别小题大作了 布莱恩 签字吧
Don't make a big deal out of this, Bryan. Just sign the paper.
- 什么? - 我不放心
- What? - I'm not comfortable with this.
- 爸爸 - 我了解这个世界 宝贝
- Dad. - I know the world, sweetie.
- 爸爸 求你了 - 一个17岁的姑娘不该单独出行
- Dad, please. - A 17-year-old should not travel alone.
- 我不是一个人啊 - 两个17岁的
- I'm not gonna be alone. - Two 17-year-olds.
阿曼达19岁了
Amanda's 19.
这样如何? 我和你们一起去?
How about this? How about if I go along?
你们不会看到我的 我很擅长做隐形人
You won't know I'm there. I'm very good at being invisible.
你就不能少操点心
As you so amply demonstrated for most of her life.
签字吧 布莱恩
Just sign the paper, Bryan.
我要想想
I'll think about it.
我们都知道那表示什么
Everyone at this table knows what that means.
嘿 金米 有件好事告诉你
Hey, Kimmy, there's something else.
- 我不想听 - 金米
- I don't want anything else. - Kim.
- 真搞不懂你 - 怎么?
- I don't get you. - What?
为了国家你牺牲了我们的婚姻
You sacrificed our marriage in the service of the country.
为了国家你把自己的生活搞得一团糟
You made a mess of your life in service of your country.
这次你就不能为你女儿牺牲一点吗?
Can't you sacrifice a little this time for your daughter?
- 我愿意为她牺牲一切 - 那到底是什么问题?
- I would sacrifice anything for her. - What's your problem?
我不放心让女儿去冒险
I'm not comfortable putting my daughter at risk.
去巴黎就是让女儿去冒险?
Putting our daughter at risk by going to Paris?
你真可悲
You're pathetic.
- 她来了 - 谢谢
- She's coming. - Thanks.
三个条件
Three conditions.
你住的地址和电话
The address and phone number of where you're staying.
和谁出门 出门去哪里
You move, I wanna know where and with whom you'll be staying.
到了给我打电话 每晚睡前给我打电话
Call me when you land. Call me every night before you go to sleep.
这是全球漫游的 我的号码在里面
It's international. My number is in.
- 好吧 真嗦 - 金米 你没在听
- Okay, awesome. - Kimmy, you're not focused.
- 在听呀 - 我都说了什么?
- I am. - What did I say?
你说到了给你打电话 每晚睡前给你打电话...
You said call you when I land, every night before I go to sleep...
...你的手机是全球漫游的 你的号码就存在里面
...your phone's international, the number's programmed in.
很好 最后一件事 我送你去机场
Okay, one last thing. I get to take you to the airport.
好吧
Okay.
- 拿去吧 - 耶
- There you go. - Yes.
谢谢 爸爸 谢谢 谢谢 太谢谢了
Thank you, Daddy. Thank you, thank you, thank you.
妈妈!
Mom!
我爱你 爸爸
I love you, Dad.
妈妈 他签了 他签了 我要去给阿曼达打电话!
Mom, he signed it, he signed it. I'm gonna go call Amanda!
一开始就签了不就好了?
Wouldn't it have been easier to sign the first time?
你跟我先谈下不更好?
Wouldn't it have been easier if you and I had talked about it first?
在巴黎要注意的地方我都写下来了
Certain areas in Paris you should avoid. I've written them down.
- 爸爸 - 来 拿去
- Dad. - Come on, take it.
大部分时间我们都会在博物馆 别担心
We're gonna be spending 90 percent of our time in museums. Don't worry.
就像说沾水不会弄湿一样 宝贝
That's like telling water not to be wet, sweetie.
妈妈说你的工作让你神经质
Mom says your job made you paranoid.
不 我的工作使我警觉
Well, my job made me aware.
我以前总是问妈妈你是做什么的 为什么你老不在家
I used to ask Mom what your job was that you were away all the time.
而她让我自己问你
And she would tell me to ask you.
每次看到你 我都不敢问
Whenever I did see you, I was afraid to ask.
是吗? 为什么呢?
Yeah? Why?
不知道 也许是因为...
I don't know. Maybe because...
...我害怕发现
...I was afraid to find out.
也许是些我不喜欢的
Like, maybe it was something I wouldn't like.
我为政府工作 你知道的
I worked for the government. You knew that.
就像一个间谍 对吗?
So you were like a spy, right?
- 如果我按下这个按钮会怎么样? - 别碰
- What happens if I push this button? - Don't touch that button.
呃 不 事实上 我是... 我是负责防护工作的
Well, no, I was a... I was a preventer, actually.
- 防护? - 是的
- A preventer? - Yeah.
防护些什么?
What did you prevent?
防止坏事发生
Bad things from happening.
那是个好工作?
So it was a good job?
对 是的
Yes. Yep, it was.
你怀念它吗?
Do you miss it?
我更想念你
I missed you more.
- 金米! - 爸爸 是阿曼达
- Kim! - Dad, there's Amanda.
去吧 我来拿包
Go ahead. I'll get the bags.
- 金米会帮你拿的 - 我自己能行
- Jimmy'll give you a hand with those. - I can manage.
勒诺
Lenore.
你知道吗? 她不仅仅去巴黎
Do you know about this? She's not just going to Paris.
- 我知道 - 她对我撒谎
- I know. - She lied to me.
是的 因为她没法对你说实情
Yes, because she can't be honest with you.
为什么? 什么意思?
Why? What are you talking about?
你老说规矩啊条件啊
Your rules and conditions.
这是什么?
What is this?
U2的欧洲巡演日程
It's U2's European tour dates.
她要跟随一个摇滚乐队环游欧洲?
She's following a rock band around Europe?
孩子们都这样 斯图尔特帮她搞到了票 为她安排了最好的酒店
All kids do. Stuart got her tickets, arranged her to stay in the best hotels.
最好的酒店 知道吗 你住在自己的小圈子里...
Best hotels. You know, you live in your little bubble here...
...有仆人和司机供差遣
...behind your wall, with your maids and chauffeurs and servants.
根本不知道外面的真实世界
No idea what the world is like.
是的 可她也不知道 所以才要出去体验一下
Yes, and neither will she unless she goes out and experiences it.
不要说我不懂这个世界
Don't tell me I don't know the world.
五年来我一直在等你的电话 你总是好几周都不打回来
For five years I waited for a phone call that didn't come for weeks at a time.
我总是担心会有人敲门 告诉我你已经死了
For a knock on the door telling me there'd be no calls anymore.
听着 我知道你搬来这 是为了重建你和金米的关系
Listen, I know you moved here to build some sort of relationship with Kimmy.
但你不能这样管着她
But you're not gonna do that by smothering her.
让她去吧 否则我肯定 我肯定你会失去她
Let her live, or I promise, I promise you'll lose her.
姑娘们
Girls.
金米!
Kim!
我爱你们
I love you.
走吧 走
Let's go. Come on.
我会教你法语
I'll teach you the French words I know.
- 我会的也不多 但是... - 好的 太棒了
- Which may not be that much, but... - Okay. Yeah, right.
三 好了 照张...
Three. Okay, now take one...
要帮忙吗? 帮你们俩合影?
Need some help? One with the two of you?
好的 谢谢
Yes, please.
- 好了 - 他长得真不错
- Okay. - He's really cute.
好了 不错 很漂亮
Okay. Yeah, great. Very nice.
你们从哪来的?
Where are you from?
加利福尼亚
California.
我叫彼得
No. I'm Peter.
- 这是金米 - 你好
- This is Kim. - Hi.
- 很高兴见到你 - 你好
- Nice to meet you. - Hi.
嗨
Hey.
你们要去巴黎?
You're going into Paris?
你们知道 这的出租车贵的要死
You know, taxis here are so damned expensive.
一起搭车如何?
Want to share?
- 好的 当然可以 - 太好了
- Yeah. Sure. - Okay, perfect.
谢谢
Thanks.
查询航班抵达 请按1
To check arrivals, please press one.
请输入航班
Please enter the flight number.
288号航班在当地时间上午8点...
Flight 288 arrived in Paris Charles de Gaulle...
...抵达巴黎戴高乐机场
...at 8 a.m. Local time.
耶
Yeah.
哦 不是真的吧?
Oh, are you serious?
- 哦 我的天 - 这地方真不错
- Oh, my God. - Nice address.
哦 是啊 谢谢
Oh, yeah, thanks.
这是我表亲的 不过他们还在马德里 所以这整个地方就是我们的了
It's my cousins', but they're in Madrid, so we have the whole place to ourselves.
很酷吧?
How cool is that?
- 我都不知道 - 又没什么大不了的
- I didn't know that. - It's no biggie.
我得走了
Well, I have to be going.
- 很高兴认识你们 - 哦 好的
- Nice to meet you. - Oh, okay.
- 我们也很高兴认识你 - 再见
- You too. - Bye.
嘿
Hey.
今晚学校有个派对 来吗?
There is a party tonight at school. Want to come?
- 当然 - 我们跟他不熟
- Sure. Yeah. - We don't even know him.
又有什么关系? 他很帅
What is there to know? He's hot.
- 我9点来接你们? - 好的
- I come pick you up around 9? - Okay, yeah.
好的 你们的公寓是?
Okay, great. Your apartment?
- 整个五楼都是 姓霍夫曼 - 好的 晚上见 拜拜
- It's the whole fifth floor. Hoffmann. - Okay. See you tonight. Bye.
再见
Bye.
对
Yeah.
五楼
Fifth floor.
两个18岁左右的女孩
Two girls around 18.
哦 天哪
Oh, my God.
- 完蛋了? - 你没搞错吧? 这太棒了
- How sick is this? - Are you kidding me? It's great.
你应该告诉我他们不在这
I just wish you would've told me they weren't gonna be here.
- 有什么关系? - 我跟我爸爸说他们在的
- What's the difference? - I told my dad they'd be here.
你还跟你爸说你会去博物馆呢
You told your dad you were going to museums too.
哦 得了 他不会知道的
Oh, come on. He's not gonna know.
- 我要和他上床 - 谁?
- I'm gonna sleep with him. - Who?
- 彼得 - 你才认识他
- Peter. - You just met him.
听说法国人床上功夫都很好
I hear French guys are amazing in bed.
- 也许他带了个朋友 哈? - 不会吧
- Maybe he has a friend, huh? - No.
- 不会吧 - 哦 拜托
- No. - Oh, come on.
迟早会有第一次 还不如在巴黎呢
You gotta lose it sometime. Might as well be in Paris.
嘿!
Hey!
- 阿曼达 洗手间在哪? - 什么?
- Amanda, where's the bathroom? - What?
我要上厕所!
I have to pee!
- 喂? - 是我 金米给你打电话了吗?
- Hello? - It's me. Has Kim called you?
布莱恩 她17岁了 她在巴黎 给她点空间
Bryan, she's 17. She's in Paris. Give her some space.
她会打给你的 吃片安眠药
She'll call. Take a sleeping pill.
喝点酒什么的 晚安
Have a drink or something. Good night.
晚安
Good night.
嗨 爸爸
Hi, Daddy.
金米
Kim.
我怎么说的? 你该打电话给我
What did I say? You were supposed to call me.
对不起
I'm sorry.
我以为手机坏了
I thought something was wrong with the phone.
- 不 在机场太忙了 - 好吧
- No. It was such a rush at the airport. - All right.
要是我有你那边的号码...
Well, if I'd had the number where you were staying...
...我就直接打到那了
...I would've just called there.
那边的电话是多少?
What's the number?
- 我还不知道 - 金米 说吧
- I don't have it. - Kimmy, come on.
这是条件之一 让我跟表亲她们讲话
This is one of the conditions. Let me talk to the cousins.
我会问她们的
I'll get it from them.
爸爸 她们在西班牙 我不知道 我发誓
Dad, they're in Spain. I didn't know. I swear.
西班牙?
To Spain?
金米 还有什么没告诉我的?
Kim, is there anything else you want to tell me?
金米
Kimmy.
- 有人来了 - 表亲她们回来了?
- There's someone here. - The cousins are back?
不是
No.
- 哦 天哪 他们抓了阿曼达 - 什么?
- Oh, my God. They got Amanda. - What?
你在说什么? 金米?
What are you talking about? Kimmy?
- 爸爸 - 金米
- Dad. - Kim.
- 金米 - 爸爸 他们抓了她
- Kim. - Dad. They took her.
- 他们抓住了她 - 好的 听我说
- They took her. - All right, listen to me.
哦 天哪
Oh, God.
- 飞机上你们有遇到谁吗? - 没有
- Did you meet anyone on the plane? - No.
- 机场呢? - 没有 不 彼得
- In the airport? - No. Yes, Peter.
- 彼得? 谁是彼得? - 我不认识
- Peter? Peter who? - I don't know.
- 美国人? - 不是
- An American? - No.
他知道你们住哪吗?
Did he know where you were staying?
他和我们一起搭的出租车
He took a cab with us.
爸爸 他们来了
Dad, they're coming.
- 救救我 我好怕 - 我知道
- Please, I'm scared. - I know you are.
集中精力 金米 别分心
Stay focused, Kimmy. You have to hold it together.
有多少人?
How many people are there?
- 三个 四个 我不确定 - 你的位置在哪?
- Three, four. I don't know. - Where are you?
- 我在洗手间 - 到隔壁的卧室去
- I'm in the bathroom. - Go to the next bedroom.
躲在床底下 躲好了告诉我
Get under the bed. Tell me when you're there.
- 好了 - 接下来非常重要
- I'm here. - Now, the next part is very important.
他们要抓你 金米 精神集中 宝贝 这是关键
They are going to take you. Kim, stay focused, baby. This is key.
你有五秒 也许10秒的时间 时间紧迫
You will have five, maybe ten seconds. Very important seconds.
把电话扔在地上 集中注意力
Leave the phone on the floor. Concentrate.
把你看到的都说出来 发色 瞳色 身高 疤痕等等
Shout out everything you see about them. Hair color, eye color, tall, short, scars.
看到的一切 明白吗?
Anything you see. You understand?
他们来了 我能听见
They're there. I can hear them.
记住 全神贯注
Remember, concentrate.
把电话放近点 我才听得到
Put the phone closer so I can hear.
他们走了 我觉得他们...
They're leaving. I think they're...
有胡子 六英尺高 右手有月亮和星星的纹身
Beard. Six feet. Tattoo right hand, moon and star.
我不知道你们是谁
I don't know who you are.
我不知道你们想要什么
I don't know what you want.
如果你们要赎金 我可以告诉你们 我没钱
If you are looking for a ransom, I can tell you, I don't have money.
但是我还是有些特别的手段的
But what I do have are a very particular set of skills.
都是我在漫长的职业生涯中学到的
Skills I've acquired over a very long career.
而这正是像你们这样的人的噩梦
Skills that make me a nightmare for people like you.
如果你们放过我女儿 那么这件事到此结束
If you let my daughter go now, that'll be the end of it.
我不会去找你们 也不会追查你们
I will not look for you. I will not pursue you.
如果你们不就此罢手 我会找到你们
But if you don't, I will look for you.
我会找到你们...
I will find you...
...然后杀了你们
...and I will kill you.
祝你好运
Good luck.
萨姆 是我 我需要帮助
Sam, it's me. I need a favor.
我下载了些东西 帮我分析下 马上
I'm gonna download something. I need it analyzed. Right now.
- 她被抓了 - 什么?
- She's been taken. - What?
- 国外的仇人? - 为什么我会有仇人?
- Any enemies overseas? - Why would I have enemies?
你在海外利用多家空壳公司做生意
You do business overseas through multiple shell corporations.
你和一伙俄罗斯人的石油生意 越来越糟糕
You were involved in an oil deal with a bunch of Russians that went south.
- 你怎么知道的? - 我不会让我的女儿...
- How do you know that? - I was not gonna let my daughter...
...和不知底细的人住一起
...live with someone without knowing everything about them.
- 我有不少可靠消息... - 现在不是玩侦探的时候
- I have a few resources... - Now is not the time for dick measuring.
- 有人要伤害你? - 就我所知没有
- Anyone looking to hurt you? - Not that I know.
- 哪个房间是金米的? - 发生了什么事?
- Which room's Kim's? - What happened?
我接到她的电话 有人在公寓里 她被抓了
I got a call from her. There were people in the apartment. She was taken.
- 哦 天哪 - 哪个房间?
- Oh, God. - Which one?
那间
That one.
我能做点什么?
Is there something I should be doing?
你的公司和NetJet航空公司有租约吧
You have a lease agreement with NetJet through your company.
是的
I do.
- 帮我弄架去巴黎的飞机 - 什么时候要?
- Get me a plane to Paris. - For when?
越快越好
An hour ago.
- 我要打个电话 你还好吧? - 我没事
- I'm gonna make the call. You all right? - Yeah, yeah. I'm okay.
拜托你把她带回来好吗 布莱恩?
Would you please get her back to me, Bryan?
首先我得找到她
First I have to find her.
萨姆 有什么发现?
Sam, what have you got?
他们说阿尔巴尼亚语
They're speaking Albanian.
从语音语调来看 他们一定来自卓帕加
Based on their accents and dialects, they must be from Tropoja.
那地方是人渣们的巢穴
The place is ground zero for scummers.
就连俄罗斯人都对这些家伙敬而远之
Even the Russians give these guys a wide berth.
跟你讲话的那个叫马科
The one you spoke to, his name is Marko.
我们收到消息...
We have information that a mobster boss...
...一个叫马科・霍查的黑道老大 六个月前搬去了巴黎
...by the name of Marko Hoxha moved to Paris about six months ago.
如果就是他 那就是条大鱼 另外那个纹身是帮派的标识
If he's the one, he's a big fish. The tattoo, by the way, is a group ID.
- 我开了免提还是不止你一个人在听? - 勒诺在这
- Am I on speaker or are you by yourself? - Lenore is here.
- 嘿 列尼 - 你好 萨姆
- Hey, Lennie. - Hello, Sam.
她也想听 萨姆
She needs to hear it, Sam.
那块地方的帮派专门拐卖女人
The specialty of the groups coming out of this area is trafficking in women.
- 继续 - 好的
- Keep going. - Okay.
他们之前的惯用伎俩就是向 新兴东欧国家的女人...
Their previous m.o. Was to offer women from emerging East European countries...
...像南斯拉夫 罗马尼亚 保加利亚这些国家 提供在西方做女佣和保姆的工作
...like Yugoslavia, Romania, Bulgaria, jobs in the West as maids and nannies.
一旦偷渡过来 就让她们染上毒瘾 逼迫她们做妓女
Once smuggled in, they'd addict them to drugs and turn them into prostitutes.
不过后来他们发现 直接绑架旅游中的年轻女人...
Lately, however, they've decided that it's more economical...
...更为经济 这样可以省下交通费
...just to kidnap traveling young women. Saves on transportation costs.
哦 我的小宝贝
Oh, my little baby.
还有什么?
What else?
根据这伙人的作案方式 我们的分析显示...
Based on the way these groups operate, our analyst says...
...从她被绑开始你有96个小时的时间
...you have a 96-hour window from the time she was grabbed.
- 否则呢? - 再也找不到她
- To what? - To never finding her.
不 不 不
No, no, no.
爸爸!
Daddy!
有胡子 六英尺高 右手有月亮和星星的纹身
Mustache. Six feet. Tattoo on right hand, moon and star.
爸...
Da...
祝你好运
Good luck.
哦 我的天
Oh, my God.
爸爸 他们抓住了阿曼达
Dad, they got Amanda.
哦 天哪
Oh, God.
爸爸 他们抓住了她
Dad, they got her.
他们抓住了她
They took her.
到隔壁的卧室去 躲在床底下
Go to the next bedroom. Get under the bed.
- 躲好了告诉我 - 好了
- Tell me when you're there. - I'm here.
精神集中 宝贝 把电话扔在地上
Stay focused, baby. Leave the phone on the floor.
集中注意力 把你看到的都说出来
Concentrate. Shout out everything you see about them.
发色 瞳色 身高 疤痕等等 看到的一切 明白吗?
Hair color, eye color, tall, short, scars. Anything you see. You understand?
他们来了 我能听见 记住 全神贯注
They're there. I can hear them. Remember, concentrate.
他们走了 爸爸!
They're leaving. Daddy!
爸爸!
Dad!
有胡子 六英尺高 右手有月亮和星星的纹身
Beard. Six feet. Tattoo right hand, moon and star.
爸爸!
Dad!
- 你好 - 你好
- Hi. - Hi.
- 我叫彼得 - 我叫英格丽德
- I'm Peter. - I'm Ingrid.
- 度假? - 对
- On holidays? - Yes.
- 我也是 - 哇哦
- Me too. - Cool.
这的出租车贵死了 一起搭吧?
Cabs here are so damned expensive. Want to share?
- 好的 为什么不呢? - 太好了
- Sure. Why not? - Great.
- 不好意思 - 嗨
- Excuse me. - Hey.
- 嗨 - 开车
- Hey. - Drive.
- 昨天的那两个美国女孩呢? - 我不知道
- The two American girls from yesterday? - I don't know.
下一根肋骨可会插入你的肺 那两个美国女孩 她们在哪?
The next rib drives into your lungs. The two American girls, where are they?
- 就像以前一样 - 还有其它办法吗?
- Just like the old days. - Would you have it any other way?
你我之间? 没了
Between you and me? No.
不过我做文职后 一切看起来不一样了
But now that I sit behind a desk, the world looks different.
- 你是指很无聊吧 - 我是说不同
- You mean, looks boring. - I mean different.
好吧 有点无聊 不过退休了能有趣吗?
Okay, a little boring. But is being retired any more interesting?
不能 直到我女儿昨天在巴黎失踪了
It wasn't. Until my daughter disappeared in Paris yesterday.
她和她朋友在机场就被盯上了 阿尔巴尼亚人干的
She and her friend were marked by a spotter at the airport. Albanians took her.
- 你怎么知道的? - 我退休了 又不是死了
- How do you know this? - I'm retired, not dead.
我猜你不会去报警
And I assume you don't want to go to the police.
有人告诉我 我有96个小时的时间 而那发生在16个小时前
I was told I have 96 hours. That was 16 hours ago.
- 好吧 首先我们得找到那个盯梢的 - 我找到了 但他死了
- Okay, first, we should find the spotter. - I found him, he's dead.
你找到的时候就已经死了?
You found him that way?
布莱恩 你不能这样跑来跑去 把巴黎弄得天翻地覆...
Bryan, you cannot just run around tearing down Paris...
如果有必要 我连埃菲尔铁塔都能掀翻
I'll tear down the Eiffel Tower if I have to.
- 不要忘了你在和谁说话 - 一个朋友
- Don't forget who you talk to. - I'm talking to a friend.
没错 但记住 你朋友现在是做文职的
You are. But please remember, your friend has a desk now.
"内部安全局副局长" 印象深刻
"Deputy director, Internal Security." Very impressive.
阿尔巴尼亚人?
The Albanians?
六 七年前他们从东面过来
They showed up from the East, six, seven years ago.
有15 20个的样子 而现在有几百个了
Fifteen, 20 of them. Now there are hundreds.
我们甚至都不知道他们究竟有多少人 也不知道他们的危险程度
We don't even know how many. And dangerous.
明白了 哪里可以找到他们?
So I heard. Where do I find them?
最好先从克利希酒店开始 布莱恩 不要胡来
The best place to start is Porte de Clichy. Bryan, try not to make a mess.
- 格莱格・米洛斯维克? - 是的 是的 我是格莱格
- Gregor Milocivic? - Yes. Yes, I am Gregor.
我是史密斯 上车
I'm Mr. Smith. Get in.
这是我的简历
Here is my resume.
职业介绍所让我来做翻译
The employment agency said we would be doing translations.
是的 阿尔巴尼亚语翻成英语 你真的会说阿尔巴尼亚语?
Yes. Albanian to English. You do speak Albanian?
阿尔巴尼亚语 塞尔维亚语 克罗地亚语 普里什蒂纳发生战争前...
Albanian, Serbian, Croatian. I was a teacher in primary school...
...我是个小学老师... - 你的时薪多少?
...before the war began in Pristina... - What's your rate?
我的时薪?
My rate?
前三个小时25元每小时 之后涨到...
It is 25 per hour for the first three hours and then it goes up...
好的 给 这是10个小时的 等在这
Okay. Now, here's for 10 hours. Wait here.
史密斯先生 我不明白 我到底要做什么?
Mr. Smith, I do not understand. What is the job exactly?
现在就是在这等着
Right now the job is to wait here.
晚上好
Good evening.
- 嘿 找伴吗? - 我喜欢你的衣服 丝质的?
- Hi. Looking for a date? - I love your dress. Is that silk?
不知道 想知道价钱吗?
I don't know. You want to know the prices?
这么笔挺 一定是丝质
Just the way it falls, it must be silk.
完全凸显了你的自然曲线
How it compliments the natural curves of your body.
标准服务40欧元
The rate is 40 euros for the standard.
标准服务? 能更具体点吗?
Standard? Could you be more specific?
回到家 标准的内容就更广了
Back home, the standard covers a range of possibilities.
比如亲吻 你知道的 张嘴闭嘴
Like kissing, you know, closed lips, open lips.
- 不要就滚蛋 - 我没说不要
- Lf you're not buying, piss off. - I didn't say I wasn't buying.
付钱之前我喜欢问清楚
I like to get comfortable before I purchase.
就像我买的那个卡拉OK机
Like this karaoke machine I bought.
我一定会把说明书从头到尾看上好几遍
I must have read that manual from cover to cover so many times.
这我管不着 如果你不付钱 我就麻烦了
I don't give a shit. You're gonna get me in trouble if you don't buy.
- 麻烦? 真的? 谁要找你麻烦? - 滚
- Trouble? Really? With who? - Piss off.
好吧 好吧 听着 我很抱歉
Okay, okay. Listen, I'm sorry.
如果我要整套服务 有没有折扣?
If I want a package deal, do I get a discount?
- 你已经让我错过了两个客人 - 我叫布莱恩
- You cost me two now. - My name's Bryan.
- 哦 天哪 你快点走 - 我们不是在谈价嘛
- Oh, God. You better leave. - I thought we were negotiating.
安东 我发誓 不是我的错
Anton, I swear, it's not my fault.
- 我跟他说... - 你为什么纠缠这个女孩?
- I told him... - Why are you bothering the girl?
- 不关你的事 - 她归我管
- None of your business. - She is my business.
要是你不花钱 就是在浪费我们的钱
And if you're not spending money, you're costing money.
- 我在谈价呢 - 没有还价 是多少就多少
- I was negotiating. - No negotiating. Price is the price.
你还欠我那两个走掉的
Now you owe me for two that got away.
我不欠你
I don't owe you nothing.
- 50欧元 否则我揍你 - 好吧 好吧 好吧
- Fifty euros or I kick your ass. - Sure, sure, okay.
冷静点
Chill.
给你 50元
Okay. Here's your 50.
这另外50元是因为你是个浑球 滚蛋吧
And another 50 for being an asshole. Now get the hell out of here.
再让我看到你 我会杀了你
If I see you again, I'll kill you.
史密斯先生 我不清楚你要我 为你做什么样的工作 但...
Mr. Smith, I do not know what kind of job I'm supposed to do for you, but...
- 你的工作是翻译 - 我知道 但翻译什么呢?
- You are to translate. - Yes. But translate what?
这个
This.
翻译
Translate.
- 他们在说你 - 说我什么?
- They're talking about you. - What about me?
- 不太好听 - 具体点
- They're not saying nice things. - Be specific.
他们在说...不好意思 史密斯先生 - 你是个浑球
They're saying... Excuse me, Mr. Smith. - What an asshole you are.
拜托 你能不能告诉我为什么要做这个...
Please, if you can explain to me why we're doing this...
翻译
Just translate.
一个人说 香肠吃得他胃痛
One of them says, the sausage gave him heartburn.
继续
Keep going.
另一个在说他的祖母以前给过他什么
The other one is suggesting something his grandmother used to give him.
- 你真的要听这个吗? - 每句话
- Do you really want to hear all this? - Every word.
现在他们在谈论足球 拉齐奥和马赛的比赛
Now they're talking about football. The game between Lazio and Marseille.
他们赌输了
And they lost money on the betting.
- 如果我知道目的... - 你最好不要知道
- Perhaps if I knew the purpose... - You're better off not knowing.
还在说足球?
Is it still football?
一个人在打电话
One is on the phone.
他得去工地办点事
He has to do a job at the construction site.
新来的货物出了点问题
Something about fresh merchandise giving problems.
史密斯先生 我一点都不明白
Mr. Smith, I do not understand any of this.
不明白最好 再见
You're not supposed to. Goodbye.
我要的英阿字典 你带来了吗?
I asked for an English-Albanian dictionary, did you bring one?
谢谢
Thank you.
我爱你
I love you.
从哪弄来的?
Where did you get this?
你从哪弄来的?
- 我很好 - 谁给你的?
- I'm good. - Who gave this to you?
- 谁...? 谁给你的? - 我很好
- Who...? Who gave this to you? - I'm good.
嗨
Hey.
坚持住
Come on.
艾伦先生 你好吗?
Monsieur Allen, how are you?
你好 吉勒斯 你妻子怎么样?
Hello, Gilles. How's the wife?
还在看护着
Well, still in charge.
- 好久不见了 - 很久了
- Been a long time since I've seen you. - Way too long.
- 老房间? - 加一间
- The usual accommodation? - Plus one.
喂?
Yes?
- 我们得谈谈 - 我听着
- We need to talk. - I'm listening.
你不先过来看看我吗?
Well, can't you come and meet me first?
我没看到你 你在哪?
I can't see you. Where are you?
我能很清楚地看到你 听到你
I can see you and hear you very well.
叫他们别跑了
You can tell them to stop jogging now.
没想到我会来 对吧?
Didn't think I was gonna come down, did you?
我没想到你会搞得这样一团糟
I didn't think you were gonna make such a mess.
我没空考虑乱不乱了
I didn't have time to worry about neatness.
- 我知道 你还有70个小时 - 现在只有56个小时了
- I know. You have 70 hours. - Now I have 56.
不 现在你一个小时也没了
No, now you have none.
我的上司要逮捕你 我说服他把你遣送回去
My chief wanted to arrest you, I convinced him to send you home.
法国航空001航班 今天2点起飞 头等舱
Air France 001 leaves today at 2. First class.
法国政府对于你过去所做贡献的特别招待
Courtesy of the French government for past services rendered.
- 我女儿怎么办? - 跟你说了 我现在是做文职的
- And what about my daughter? - I told you, I sit behind a desk now.
我得听从上司的命令
I take my orders from someone who sits behind a bigger desk.
听听 七具尸体 三个住院 一幢大楼被毁
Come on, seven dead bodies, three in hospital, a building destroyed.
还有机场的骚乱
Total chaos at the airport.
他要你坐牢 我已经尽力了 很抱歉
He wanted your ass in chains. It's the best I could do, I'm sorry.
说抱歉没用 吉恩・克劳德 这次不行
Sorry doesn't cut it, Jean-Claude. Not this time.
你斗不过政府的 布莱恩 你明白的
You can't beat the state, Bryan. You know that.
我才不想斗 我只是想救回我的女儿
I'm not trying to. I'm trying to save my daughter.
那是一辆拖车 不是大楼
It was a trailer, not a building.
不 不 不 别动它
No, no, no. Leave it.
没事 这是点滴
It's all right, it's fluids.
里面是中和毒品的药物
And medication to counteract the drugs.
没事的
It's all right.
从哪弄来的?
Where'd you get this?
你从哪弄来这件外套?
Where did you get this jacket?
从她那弄来的?
Did you get it from her?
是这个女孩的吗?
Was it from this girl?
我没偷
I didn't steal it.
- 我很冷 是她给我的 - 在哪里? 她在哪里给你的?
- I was cold, she gave it to me. - Where? Where did she give it to you?
- 房子里 - 哪座房子?
- In the house. - What house?
有扇红门的房子
The house with the red door.
对不起
Sorry.
他说那是个派对
He said it was a party.
给你外套的那个女孩在房子里吗?
The girl who gave you this, was she in the house?
她是好人
She was nice.
我知道
I know.
她是我女儿
She's my daughter.
我必须找到那座房子 你知道在哪吗?
I need to find this house. Do you know where it is?
天堂
Paradise.
- 早上好 - 有事吗?
- Good morning. - May I help you?
- 我要见你们老板 - 老板不在
- I'm here to see your boss. - No boss.
我们没做什么非法的事
We're doing nothing wrong here.
按一下 30个特工就会出现在这...
One button, and 30 agents will be here...
...你们根本没时间卷铺盖走人
...before you have time to scratch your balls.
别耍人了 再浪费我时间 小心我干掉你
Stop jerking around before I close you down for wasting my time.
在这等着
Wait here.
你带着武器?
You have weapon?
你手上拿着呢
You're holding it.
黑咖啡 一块糖 谢谢
Black, one sugar, please.
你要什么?
What is it you want?
我是来谈价钱的
I'm here to negotiate the rates.
我们和梅肯先生谈过了
We already negotiated the rate with Mr. Macon.
梅肯先生调到别的区了
Mr. Macon has moved to another division.
我是来重新谈的
I'm here for the renegotiation.
觉得我有道理的话 那我接着说了
Unless you think I'm being unreasonable, let me explain ourselves.
咖啡不错 我们利用卫星全天24小时监视你们
Nice coffee. We have you under satellite surveillance, 24 hours a day.
你们说的每句话 做的每件事 我们都知道
We hear everything you say, we know everything you do.
你知不知道 光是改变地球上空200米...
Do you have any idea what it costs just to change the angle...
...轨道卫星的镜头角度 就要花多少钱?
...of the lens on a satellite orbiting 200 miles above the Earth?
而且价格还在上涨
And those costs have gone up.
我们的费用上涨 随之你们的费用也得上涨 再正常不过了
Our costs go up, your costs go up. It's only logical.
另外 你们谁是马科?
By the way, which one of you is Marko?
你问这干嘛?
Why do you want to know?
我听说马科是这的老大
I was told Marko is in charge.
我们都是马科
We are all Marko.
马科来自卓帕加
Marko from Tropoja.
我们都来自卓帕加
We are all from Tropoja.
如果你们那么想玩游戏 那么费用上升10%
If that's the game you want to play, the rate just went up 10 percent.
不要以为我们是移民就可以敲诈我们 我们懂法律
If you are trying to extort us because we are immigrants, we know the law.
我敲诈你们是因为你们做了违法的事
I'm extorting you because you are breaking the law.
你们喜欢以哪项罪名被捕?
Which charge would you like to be arrested for?
贩毒 绑架 卖淫? 随你们挑
Drugs, kidnapping, prostitution? Take your pick.
你们来到这个国家 利用这个国家...
You come to this country, take advantage of it...
...我们宽容并不代表我们懦弱无助
...and think because we are tolerant, we are weak and helpless.
你们的傲慢无礼激怒了我
Your arrogance offends me.
为此 费用提升10%
For that, the rate went up 10 percent.
现在 你们要谈正事还是继续玩?
Now, do you want to get down to business or to keep playing?
- 多少? - 20%
- How much? - Twenty percent.
而且我保证一年内不会上涨
And you have my word it'll not go up for a year.
用你们的语言如何说"糖"?
How do you say "sugar" in your language?
你们做了明智的决定 先生们
You've made a very good investment, gentlemen.
一个月后见
See you in a month.
一个朋友给我的 是阿尔巴尼亚语 不介意翻一下吧?
A friend gave this to me. It's Albanian. You mind translating it?
祝你好运
Good luck.
- 祝你好运 - 祝你好运
- Good luck. - Good luck.
- 祝你好运 祝你好运 - 祝你好运
- Good luck. Good luck. - Good luck.
你不记得我了
You don't remember me.
两天前我们通过电话
We spoke on the phone two days ago.
我告诉过你我会找到你
I told you I would find you.
金米
Kim.
阿曼达
Amanda.
醒醒!
Wake up!
我要你集中精神
I need you to be focused.
精神集中了吗?
Are you focused yet?
这女孩在哪?
Where is this girl?
她在哪?
Where is she?
你知道 我们以前会外包这种事
You know, we used to outsource this kind of thing.
但我们发现 我们外包的那些国家...
But what we found was the countries we outsourced to...
...电网都不怎么稳定 典型的第三世界
...had unreliable power grids. Very Third World.
你按了开关 却没有电...
You'd turn on a switch, power wouldn't come on...
...真是气死人 没办法 就只能拔指甲
...and then tempers would get short. People would resort to pulling fingernails.
在裸露的皮肤上洒酸溶液
Acid drips on bare skin.
这些只会造成反效果
The whole exercise would become counterproductive.
但在这里 电力很稳定
But here, the power's stable.
这里的电流源源不断
Here, there's a nice even flow.
轻按开关 电力就能持续一整天
Here, you can flip a switch and the power stays on all day.
她在哪?
Where is she?
我可没什么时间可以浪费 卓帕加的马科
Now, I don't have any more time to waste, Marko from Tropoja.
回答我 否则这个开关会一直开着...
Give me what I need or this switch'll stay on...
...直到他们付不出电费而关掉
...till they turn power off for lack of payment on the bill.
我女儿在哪?
Where is my daughter?
我们不会留着处女 我们会卖了她们
We don't keep virgins, we sell them.
她是处女 可以卖一大笔
She was virgin, lot of money.
你把我女儿卖了? 你把她卖了?
You sold my daughter? You sold her?
卖给谁了?
To who?
我不知道
I don't know.
- 什么? - 圣・嘉力
- What? - Saint-Clair.
圣・嘉力
Saint-Clair.
圣・嘉力? 圣・嘉力 是个人 还是个地方?
Saint-Clair? Saint-Clair. Is that a person, a place?
是个人 帕特里斯・圣・嘉力
Person. Patrice Saint-Clair.
帕特里斯・圣・嘉力
Patrice Saint-Clair.
在哪能找到他?
Where can I find him?
我不知道 我不知道
I don't know, I don't know.
我不知道 我不知道 我不知道
I don't know. I don't know. I don't know.
求求你! 我真的不知道!
Please! I don't know!
我不知道! 不! 求求你! 求求你
I don't know! No! Please! Please.
求求你
Please.
不要 求求你
Not that. Please.
我相信你
I believe you.
但我不能放过你
But it's not gonna save you.
看看谁来了
Look who dropped by.
布莱恩 真是意外啊
Bryan, what a pleasant surprise.
吉恩・克劳德
Jean-Claude.
孩子们在等你
The children waited up for you.
快带他们去睡觉 我们还能吃顿热乎乎的
If you tuck them in, maybe we can eat before everything gets cold.
布莱恩 来帮下忙?
Bryan, will you do the honors?
- 好的 - 我马上来
- Sure. - I'll be just a minute.
我正跟布莱恩说 你换了新工作后...
I was just telling Bryan how nice it's been...
...一切变得好多了
...since you left the old job for the new one.
每晚回家吃饭 见到孩子们的时间也多了
Home every night for dinner, get to see the kids more.
每晚回家 看着孩子们 一定很幸福
Yeah, must be nice coming home every night, seeing your kids.
布莱恩在考虑搬家
Bryan has been thinking about relocating.
- 真的? - 是的
- Really? - Yes.
搬到巴黎 他在看房子了
To Paris, he's been visiting houses.
- 要鸡胸还鸡腿? - 鸡腿 谢谢
- White or dark meat? - Dark, please.
有看上的吗?
Find anything interesting?
说实话 有啊 在天堂街第十区
As a matter of fact, I did, in the 10th arrondissement on Rue Paradis.
住那的人认识你的一个同事
People there know someone that works in your office.
一位梅肯先生 你认识吗?
A Mr. Macon. Do you know him?
哦 亨利 我都叫他紧张先生
Oh, Henry. I call him Mr. Nervous.
总是一副会有麻烦的样子 要胡萝卜吗?
Always seems like he's about to have a problem. Carrots?
我查到了 吉恩・克劳德
I got to the bottom of it, Jean-Claude.
我什么都知道了
I know everything.
我希望你没趟进这浑水
I hope you're not involved in this shit.
- 什么浑水? - 现在不该说这些 布莱恩
- What shit? - This is not the time or place, Bryan.
- 你掺合进来了? - 掺合进什么?
- Are you involved? - Involved in what?
你们俩在说什么?
What are you two talking about?
- 是不是? - 我的薪水是X 我的开支是Y
- Are you? - My salary is X, my expenses are Y.
只要能养家...
As long as my family is provided for...
...我不在乎从哪弄钱
...I do not care where the difference comes from.
我就是那样卷进来的
That is my entire involvement.
- 那我的家人呢? - 我告诉你...
- What about my family? - I told you...
...只要不惹麻烦 我会帮你的
...I would help as long as it didn't cause trouble.
谁是帕特里斯・圣・嘉力?
Who is Patrice Saint-Clair?
我不知道 我也不关心 我载你去机场
I don't know, I don't care. I am driving you to the airport.
吉恩・克劳德
Jean-Claude.
走吧 晚餐结束了
Let's get going. Dinner is over.
- 我还没吃完 - 不 你吃完了
- I'm not finished yet. - Yes, you are.
- 不! - 不 我还没有
- No! - No, I'm not.
那就是你做文职的后果 你忘了些事
That's what happens when you sit behind a desk. You forget things.
就如你都忘了 上了弹的枪拿在手上的重量
Like the weight in the hand of a gun that's loaded.
伊莎贝尔!
Isabelle!
只是皮肉伤
It's a flesh wound.
但你再不说 就会看到你最不想看的...
But if you don't get me what I need, the last thing you'll see...
...我会射穿她的脑门
...is the bullet I put between her eyes.
现在 告诉我谁是帕特里斯・圣・嘉力
Now, Patrice Saint-Clair.
你本可以少受点苦...
You could've made this less painful...
...只要你多关心点我女儿 而不是你的职位
...if you had been more concerned about my daughter and less about your desk.
请替我向你妻子道歉
Please apologize to your wife for me.
- 能为您效劳吗? - 我来找圣・嘉力先生
- Can I help you? - Yes, I'm here to see Mr. Saint-Clair.
请告诉我您的名字
Your name, please.
抱歉 上面没有您的名字
I'm sorry, your name is not on the list.
哦 请再检查一次
Oh, please check again.
进去
Inside.
需要帮忙吗 先生?
May I help you, sir?
- 您点的香槟 - 没错 放这吧
- Your champagne. - Yeah, I will take it.
现在出价5万 5万
I have 50,000. Fifty thousand.
5万
Fifty thousand.
10万 10万
One hundred, 100,000.
10万 15万
One hundred, 150.
现在出价15万
I have 150.
您的香槟 先生
Your champagne, sir.
20万 现在出价20万 25万
Two, I have two, 250.
要为您倒酒吗?
May I serve?
- 谢谢 - 现在出价25万
- Please. - I have 250.
25万
Two-fifty.
25万成交
Sold for 250,000.
最后一件拍品
The last item.
惯例 最好的留到最后
As usual, we save the best for last.
说英语 会一点法语
Speaks English, some French.
绝对是处女
Certified pure.
- 对不起 - 出去
- Sorry. - Get out.
起价为10万
The bidding will begin at 100,000.
10万
One hundred.
One hundred thousand.
- 我说..... - 我听到了
- I said... - I heard what you said.
买下她
Buy her.
现在出价10万
I have 100.
- 买下她 - 15万
- Buy her. - One-fifty.
20万
Two hundred.
25万 30万 35万
Two-fifty, three, 350.
35万
Three hundred and fifty thousand.
40万 40万
Four. Four.
45万 45万
Four-fifty, 450.
45万
Four hundred and fifty thousand.
Four-fifty.
50万 50万
Five hundred. Five hundred thousand.
50万 成交
Five hundred thousand. Sold.
今晚的拍卖到此结束 谢谢各位的惠顾
That concludes the sales for tonight. Thank you all for coming.
- 你可以直接领走你的商品 - 走
- You can collect your purchases directly. - Move.
- 你逃不掉的 - 要是你想活着 你就得保证我也活着
- You will never get away with this. - Lf you wanna live, you'll make sure I do.
先生?
Now, Mr?
我们知道你不是这个人 但我们该怎么叫你?
Well, we know you're not this man. So, what do we call you?
我们怎么叫你不重要...
It doesn't matter what we call you...
...重要的是你来这干嘛
...what does matter is what you're doing here.
最后那女孩 我是她父亲
The last girl, I'm her father.
- 哦 我的天 - 把她还给我
- Oh, my. - Give her to me.
说实话 我希望我能
I wish I could, honestly.
看 我也是个父亲
See, I'm a father myself.
我有两个儿子 一个女儿...
I have two sons and a daughter...
...但是我必须告诉你 不管你叫什么
...but let me tell you something, Mr. Whoever-You-Are.
这是生意
This is a business.
这是和特殊客户...
This is a very unique business...
...做的特殊生意 - 我会付钱
...with a very unique clientele. - I'll pay.
这种生意 你不能退款 退货...
In this business, you have no refunds, returns...
...没有折扣 回购 一经售出便成定局
...discounts, buybacks. All sales are final.
除了决定权 这是我们唯一的一条规则
Besides discretion, it's about the only rule we have.
杀了他 安静点 我还有客人
Kill him. Quietly. I have guests.
你去看看 我让他们"安静点"...
Would you please go see which part of "quietly"...
...他们听不懂吗? - 是 先生
...they did not understand? - Yes, sir.
好吧 我们可以解决的 我明白你的感受
Okay, we can resolve this. I know how you feel.
我们谈谈 怎么样? 我们会找到办法的
We should talk, okay? We can work this out.
你不知道...
You have no idea...
- 她在哪? - 别
- Where is she? - Please.
请理解 请试着...
Understand. Please try...
码头那有条船
There's a boat by the quay.
请你明白
Please understand.
这都是生意 我们无冤无仇的
It was all business, it wasn't personal.
现在有仇了
It was all personal to me.
我们能...
We can...
- 爸爸 - 金米
- Daddy. - Kim.
你来救我了
You came for me.
我说过我会的
I told you I would.
乘客们请注意 如果各位在等你们的大号行李箱...
May I have your attention. If you're waiting for oversized bags...
妈妈
Mom.
哦 天哪
Oh, my God.
哦 宝贝
Oh, sweetie.
哦 来 我帮你拿
Oh, here, let me get that for you.
布莱恩 如果你需要什么...
Bryan, if there's anything you need...
我已经拥有了我想要的一切
I've got everything I need.
我很爱你
I love you so much.
斯图尔特
Stuart.
谢谢
Thank you.
请注意 游客们 你们不用...
Attention, travelers. You are not required to...
走了吗?
Shall we go?
你确定不用载你一程?
Sure you don't wanna ride with us?
- 没关系 我可以叫车 谢谢 - 好的
- I'll be fine. I'll take a cab. Thanks. - All right.
- 我爱你 爸爸 - 我也爱你
- I love you, Dad. - Love you too.
- 这是哪? - 跟你说了 这是一个惊喜
- Where are we? - I told you. It's a surprise.
- 你好 - 你好
- Hi. - Hi.
有人跟你说"你好"时 通常应礼貌地回应"你好"
When someone says "hi," it's usually polite to say "hi" back.
你好
Hi.
我听说你想当歌手
I heard you wanna be a singer.
- 是的 - 没错
- I do. - She does.
进来吧 让我们听听你唱得如何
Well, come on in. Let's see what you got.
主演：利亚姆・尼森
主演：麦琪・格雷斯
主演：利兰・奥泽 琼・格瑞斯 大卫・华少夫斯基
主演：霍莉・瓦莱斯 凯蒂・卡西迪
主演：山德・贝克利
主演：奥利维尔・华宝登
主演：杰拉德・沃特金斯
法米克・詹森